Okay, it's time to have some talk about
definitions and terminology.
For the past few videos, I've tried to
use simple terms, things that uh you
don't have to be a programmer to
understand, but when you have a
technical interview, they are going to
expect you to know the right word for
some of the things that we've used in
the past few videos. So, I want to give
you the right word for those so you're
not confused in an interview or um just
if in case you need to do some extra
searching about that term, I want to
give you the right term for it. So,
let's talk about some definitions. I'm
gonna share my screen real quick. All
right. So, here I've written a function
and I used the older syntax. Um, that's
because um I need it to help you
understand some definitions. So, the
first thing is that writing this right
here is called declaring a function.
When you declare a function, I told you
that you can define some places where
you can receive some input. When you
define those, we call those parameters.
So input one and input two I've called
param 1 and param 2. That is because
when you define places for input to come
into your function you are creating
parameters. So up here is called a
parameter.
When you put parentheses after a
function it is called calling the
function or executing the function.
The pieces of information that you put
into the function the actual real
information. So where I'm putting a one
or a two, those are called arguments. A
function takes arguments, stores them in
parameters, and then executes it. So
when you're defining the function,
they're called parameters. When you're
putting information in and you're
calling the function, they're called
arguments. So these are arguments. One
and two are arguments. Three and four
are arguments. Pam one and param 2 are
parameters.
Nothing has changed about how this
function works. So just to be clear,
this function still takes two pieces of
input, does some work, and returns the
output. In this case, it's taking 1 and
two as input and returning 1 + 2. In
this case, it's taking three and four as
input and returning 3 + 4. So nothing
has changed, but the definition of the
word is that down here, these are called
arguments. Up here in the definition of
the function, they're called parameters.
The next thing I want to talk about is
the thing I've called shorthand
functions. So if you wanted to create a
function where you say um where you put
the parentheses,
you put the little arrow and then
you write
maybe you take a and b and you return a
plus b. So this right here is called a
lambda function or an arrow function.
It's called an arrow because of this
little arrow here. Um, but this is
called a lambda function. So, I called
them shorter functions or shorthand
functions in the previous videos, but if
you're ever talking to an employer and
they want you to use the actual term,
this is called a lambda function. And
occasionally in slang, it's called an
arrow function. So hopefully that helps
with definitions in case um you have
anything in an interview, you won't get
caught by surprise.